（ナルト）風遁　超大玉螺旋手裏剣！
Wind Style:
Massive Rasen Shuriken!
Inferno Style:
Susano'o Flame Control!
（サスケ）炎遁　須佐能乎加具土命！
((いや　そっちじゃなくて。
No... That's not what I meant.
Only "Wind" can assist
and magnify "Fire..."
火を助けて
更に大きな力にできるのは→
(風の力だけだってことだ))
ヘッ。
燃え尽きろ。
Burn away!
You heard what
Sasuke said earlier, didn't you?
（サイ）サスケの言ったこと
キミも　見て聞いていただろう。
彼の本当の狙いは　なんなんだ。
What are his true intentions?
（重吾）さあな。
I have no idea.
（カツユ）不完全ですが復活した十尾と
連合軍が交戦中と→
Though still incomplete,
the Ten Tails has been revived
and is battling the Allied Forces.
かなり複雑な状況だと
推測できます。
So I think that it's become
quite a complex situation.
（綱手）そこまで…。
It's gotten that bad...
なら　我々も急ぐとしよう。
In that case, we need to hurry!
（我愛羅）俺の砂でみんなを運ぶ。
I'll carry everyone with my sand.
チャクラを温存してくれ。
Please save your chakra.
話の途中からだ。
詳しく知りたい。
We came in mid-story.
I want more details!
移動中にでも聞け。
Ask about them while we're en route.
早く行きましょう　戦場へ。
Let's go as fast as we can...
to the battlefield!
Kakashi vs. Obito
Then why do you work with Sasuke?
（サイ）ならキミが　サスケと行動を
ともにしているのは→
どうしてだい？
Because I exist to protect him.
俺はサスケを守るために
存在しているからだ。
サスケ！　あのでけえやつの中には
尾獣たちが入ってんだ。
Sasuke! There are other Tailed Beasts
inside that huge one!
弱りきったら
黒い炎を止めてくれ。
Once it's weakened,
shut off your Black Flames!
俺と九喇嘛で引っ張り出すから。
Then Kurama and I will
pull them out of it!
ダメだ　このまま焼き尽くす。
No.
They all burn.
おい　わかってんのか！
あいつら助けねえと！
Hey! Don't you get it?
If we don't save them now,
あとあといろいろ　めんどくせえ
ことに　なるんだってばよ！
we'll end up facing
a lot of trouble later on!
《今までの負のシステムは
すべて俺が始末をつける》
I'm going to put an end to
this failing system currently in place!
And then, a new...
《そして新たな…》
チッ。
It detached the piece of itself
that was on fire!
《燃えている部分だけ
分離したか》
サクラ　少し聞いていいかな？
Sakura... Can I ask you something?
Since I don't know him very well,
I can look at this objectively.
僕は彼をよく知らないから
冷静に見れる。
サスケ君は
本当の仲間として信用できない。
Sasuke cannot be trusted
as a true comrade.
キミはほんとは
どう思ってるんだい？　サクラ。
What are your true feelings
on the matter, Sakura?
Don't worry,
Sasuke has come back to us.
（サクラ）大丈夫。　サスケ君は
ちゃんと帰ってきてくれた。
私は　そのことが嬉しいし
彼のこと信用もしてる。
I'm happy about that.
And I do trust him.
Your words may not be lies...
《キミの言葉は
ウソじゃないのかもしれない。
でも　キミの笑顔がウソだってのは→
But...
I can already tell that
your smile is fake.
もう　わかるんだよ》
What's up, Shikamaru?
（いの）シカマル　どうかした？
（シカマル）いや。
It's nothing...
（カカシ）オビト。
Obito...
この手のひっかけはいいだろう。
Enough of these tricks...
（カカシ）もう　あきあきだ。
I'm over it.
No more genjutsu.
幻術は終わりだ。
どうやら俺には→
Looks like I can't find anything
that will change you.
お前を変えるだけのものが
見つからない。
もう　お前にしてやれるのは
死だけだ。
Right now, all I can give you...
...is death.
（オビト）なら　俺も同じだ　来い。
Then I shall do the same.
Come!
((ミナト：では　忍組手　始め))
All right!
Shinobi Hand-to-Hand Combat!
Begin!
うおっ…。
借りるぞ。
I'm going to borrow this.
うおっ…。
((火遁…))
Fire Style...
《豪火球の術》
Fireball Jutsu!
((土遁…))
Earth Style...
Mud Wall!
《土流壁》
《本命はこっち》
The real one is here!
うわっ…。
（オビト）うわっ。
((組手は終わり。
Hand-to-hand combat is over.
Kakashi wins.
カカシの勝ちだね。
(さあ　和解の印を))
Now perform the Unison Sign.
《カカシ：オビト　かつての
お前の意思は　今でも→
Obito...
Your once strong will is
still alive today, right next to me!
俺の隣にいる。
今の俺にできることは→
What the current me can do
is protect the current Naruto!
今のナルトを守ることだ》
((オビト：お前も　いや誰でもいずれ→
You will...
Actually, everyone will
eventually end up just like me.
(俺のようになるのだからな))
((カカシ：サスケは　抜け忍だ→
Sasuke is a Rogue Ninja.
Standard procedure is to erase him.
普通は　抹殺するのがセオリーだ。
サスケは　ぜってえ俺が連れ帰る。
I'll bring back Sasuke!
仲間一人　救えねえやつが→
Someone who can't even save
one of their friends
火影になんてなれるかよ。
could never become Hokage!
俺は　どの先代をも超える
火影になる。
I'm going to surpass every Hokage
who came before me!
(俺の仲間は絶対
殺させやしねえ))
- I'd never kill any of my friends!
（カカシ）ナルト　お前は決して迷わない。
Naruto... You never waver.
俺より強く
お前だけのものがたくさんある。
You're stronger than me and
you have many things
that are solely yours.
今の俺には　これしかできない。
This is all I can do right now.
俺は　俺のできることを。
And that is...
この世界を　仲間を…。
to protect this world, my comrades...
かつてのオビトを守ることは→
and the Obito of the past...
今のオビトを…。
by killing...
殺すこと。
the current Obito!
うぅっ　ぐぁっ！
うぅ…。
あ…　ぐっ…。
終わりだよ…　オビト。
It's over, Obito.
ハハハ…。
こ　この…　戦いは…
お前の勝ちでいい。
I'll let you win...
this battle.
But I'm not conceding the war!
だが　戦争の勝ちは譲らん。
（マダラ）分身とやるつもりはないと
言ったはずだ。
I thought I told you.
I have no intention of fighting a clone.
仕掛けてくるのはいいが
手ごたえがまるでないぞ。
You can come at me with them,
but they offer no resistance at all.
You're concentrating too much power
in your actual body.
本体で力を集中しすぎだ。
（柱間）マダラ　お前もずっと
何かを…。
Madara... All the time, you kept
holding something back...
あれは…。
That's...
うぅっ！　ああ…。
Looks like that's of no use
to me anymore.
《マダラ：あれはもう
使いものにならんか。
人柱力になる前に　柱間と
やってみたかったのだがな。
I wanted to fight Hashirama
before I became a Jinchuriki...
しかたない》
I guess I have no choice.
ぐぁっ！　ああ！
《体が！》
M-My body!
《俺を　輪廻転生させる頃合いだ》
It's time to make him bring me back
with Rinne Rebirth!
うぅっ！
うぉ～！
《あれは！》
That's...!
うぅ…　うぅ！
オビト　お前は俺を
よみがえらせるために→
Obito...
You're just a backup that
I had cultivated for my rebirth.
手なずけておいた予備だ。
((オビト：じいちゃんが
助けてくれたのか？
You saved me, Gramps?
ありがとう。
Thank you.
礼を言うのは　まだ早い。
It's too early to thank me.
(その分の恩は　しっかり
返してもらうつもりだ))
I intend to have you...
...repay your debt.
That time is now.
今こそ　返してもらう。
（オビト）うぉ～！
《マダラのチャクラで操られている》
He's being controlled by
Madara's chakra!
The Six Paths Forbidden...
《六道の禁術→
Rinne Rebirth Jutsu?
輪廻転生というやつか！？
マダラ！　やつを完全に
生き返らせてはならん》
Madara... He must not be allowed
to fully return to life!
（柱間）
少年たちよ　お前たちが近い。
Lads!
You're all closer!
Stop the jutsu of the one
on top of the Ten Tails right now!
今すぐ　十尾の上の者を
止めてくれ。
ああ　わか…　サスケ！
Okay! Got—
Sasuke!
I see...
そうか…　そういうことか。
So that's how it is.
《この結界中にできる分身は
これが限界か》
Is this the maximum amount
I can make inside this barrier?
Tobirama!
扉間！
（扉間）おう！
Okay!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
影分身の術。
Only two.
たった２体…
わしも　このザマとは。
Is this also the best I can do?
だが　これでやるしかない。
We'll just have to make do with this!
オビトの側が間に合わぬと踏んで
俺自身への攻撃準備…。
They can't get to Obito in time,
so they're going to attack me...
わかっているはずだ。
They should know by now
that I can't be stopped with clones.
分身ではこの俺は止められぬと。
ウググッ！
アオダ　もういい。　消えてろ！
That's enough, Aoda!
You can get out of here!
Yes, Lord Sasuke!
（アオダ）はっ　サスケ様。
チッ！
((お前も今のままじゃ
ないはずだよね。
You won't always be
like this either, right?
諦めるな。
Don't give up.
リン　大好きなんだろう。
You love Rin, don't you?
(俺たちは火影になる))
We'll both become Hokage.
《だろ？　オビト》
Right, Obito?
先生。
Sensei...
オビト。
Obito!
お前…　だったのか。
That...was you?
どっちぞ？
Which one is he?
失敗だ。
What a failure!
が　まあいい。
But...oh well!
やったのか？
あれは四代目火影様だ！
Did they succeed?!
That's Lord Fourth Hokage!
《影分身で瞬身の術。
やつにマーキングしていたのか？》
He teleported a Shadow Clone.
Had he marked him already?
飛雷神のマーキングは決して消えない。
A Flying Raijin marking
never disappears.
それは教えてなかったね　オビト。
I didn't teach you that, did I, Obito?
（ミナト）生きていたなら
火影になってほしかった。
If you were alive,
I would have wanted you
to become Hokage...
なぜ…。
Why did you...?
あっけなかったな。
That was disappointing...
あとは　あの生き返り損ねた
マダラを封印すれば→
All that's left to do is to seal
the un-reborn Madara...
この戦争も終わりだ。
and this war will be over.
それと　このデカブツもな。
As well as this giant thing.
何をもって終戦と決めつける？
What makes you think
the war is over...
裏切り者の同胞よ。
my fellow traitor?
クッ！
父ちゃん　サスケ！
Dad! Sasuke!
ガマ吉！
（ガマ吉）オゥ！
Gamakichi!
Okay!
なんだ？　何が？
What? What's happening?!
十尾がまた形態変化したのか？
Is the Ten Tails changing
form again?
いや　違う。
No, that's not what's happening!
マダラに操られてるのを
振り払って→
He shook off Madara's manipulation and
こいつは最初からずっと
これになるために印を結んでた。
was weaving the signs
to do this from the beginning!
あれは…。
That's...
十尾の人柱力だってばよ！
...the Ten Tails' Jinchuriki!
Oh! I really want to know
what happens next!
But the next episode will
be a little breather.
It's an "Extra Edition!"
Pain and Itachi appear again!
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Even more, Deidara and
Pervy Sage appear
美空ひばりです。
and cause a big ruckus
in the Leaf Village!
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
What kind of a story is this?
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
今回はご覧の豪華な歌手の
皆さんによる→